<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Casual-writing on The J Word</title>
    <link>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Casual-writing on The J Word</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
      <title>Github tools</title>
      <link>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/github_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/github_tools/</guid>
      <description>This article is used to organize some helpful open source gadgets that I have found, and also share them with friends who see this article. Please check the Chinese version. The English version will not be updated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SLAI Application</title>
      <link>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/phd_application/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/phd_application/</guid>
      <description>This passage is a personal record of my PhD application journey. It focuses on the basic requirements of the process and my reflections on participating in it.Application and Exam Preparation I received the application notice from the department and my supervisor at the end of February. Shortly after that, the Shenzhen Loop Area Institute (SLAI) gave a presentation on the first-year student application process. The talk covered the examination details, program benefits, and overall objectives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chitchat</title>
      <link>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/abroad/chitchat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/abroad/chitchat/</guid>
      <description>This article discusses my various thoughts and the information I collected on studying abroad during the process of continuous learning. You are welcome to add to it.Two sides of studying abroad Advantages Bilingual skill More personal time and more efficient Diversified Talents (Cultural Integration) A variety of options Drawbacks Loneliness Cultural differences Lack of domestic relationships Unfamiliarity with the domestic environment (missed campus recruitment, insensitive to the job market, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UK</title>
      <link>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/abroad/uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/abroad/uk/</guid>
      <description>This article is used to record some of the information I have learned during the application process for studying abroad, for your reference. It should be added that I am an academic master in China.Language requirements Basic requirement: IELTS 6.5 (sub-score 6) Advanced requirement: IELTS 7 (sub-score 6.5) Advanced requirement: IELTS 7.5 (sub-score 7) Timeline The following is a rough timeline. It should be noted that the UK does not require GRE, only IELTS scores Material preparation Statement of Purpose Personal Statement (PS) Resume (CV) Letter of recommendation English transcripts of undergraduate and master&amp;rsquo;s degrees Language scores (TOEFL/IELTS &amp;amp; GRE/GMAT, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USA</title>
      <link>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/abroad/usa/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jackwu925.github.io/posts/casual-writing/abroad/usa/</guid>
      <description>This article is used to record some of the information I have learned during the application process for studying abroad, for your reference. It should be added that I am an academic master in China.Language requirements Most of the top universities in the United States require IELTS scores ≥ 7.5, TOEFL scores ≥ 102, and GRE scores ≥ 319 for doctoral applications (the specific request depends on the application situation of the year)</description>
    </item>
    
    
  </channel>
</rss>
